（泰瑞莎邦德 1943-69 詹姆斯邦德爱妻）
（我们还有很多时间）
邦德先生 真高兴你还没走
Mr. Bond, Mr. Bond, I'm so glad I caught you.
你办公室来电 说派了直升机来接你
Your office called. They're sending a helicopter to pick you up.
好像事态紧急
Some sort of emergency.
通常都是急事 谢谢你
It usually is. Thank you.
午安 邦德先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Bond.
别担心驾驶
Don't concern yourself with the pilot.
他是我比较没用的手下
One of my less useful people.
你正在搭乘遥控航空班机
You are now flying Remote Control Airways.
你得考虑清楚 007 这里离地面还有段距离
Think twice, 007. It's a long way down.
我等这一刻等了好久 邦德先生
I've looked forward to this moment, Mr. Bond.
我会尽情地享受
I intend to enjoy it to the full.
你一点都不尊重死者吗？
Really, have you no respect for the dead?
再见了 邦德先生
Goodbye, Mr. Bond.
我相信你会享受 这段惊吓的旅程
I trust you had a pleasant…fright.
你的大限将至
You are fading from my picture, Mr. Bond.
而尽头就在不远处
But the end cannot be far away.
（电路）
邦德先生
Mr. Bond! Mr. Bond!
我们可以谈条件！
We can do a deal!
你要什么我都愿意给你
I'll buy you a delicatessen in stainless steel.
求求你
Please!
好吧 坐稳了
All right, keep your hair on.
放我下来
Put me down! Put me down!
你想下去吗？
Oh, you want to get off?
邦德先生！
Mr. Bond!
《007系列之最高机密》
（圣乔治号 法勒他）
午安 上面情形如何？
Afternoon. How's it looking topside?
天气很好 刚刚才收网
Beautiful day. Just bringing the nets in.
晚餐还是吃鱼
Fish for supper again.
这是从苏联卫星资料译码得来的 是英美船舰位置资料
Decode of Russian satellite data, sir, on British and American ship positions.
- 加以核对并告诉上将 - 是 长官
- Verify and advise Admiralty. - Yes, sir.
- 午安 长官 - 你好 麦克
- Afternoon, sir. - Oh, hello, Mac.
轮到我值班了
My watch.
这是从哪冒出来的？
Where the hell did that come from?
- 发生什么事？- 不明物体迅速接近
- What the deviI's going on here? - An unidentified object closing fast.
保卫控制室
Secure Operation Room.
摧毁ATAC系统
Destruct ATAC system.
（国防部）
- 什么事？- 海军大臣跟中将来了
- Yes? - First Sea Lord and Vice Admiral, sir.
请他们进来
Send them in.
有坏消息 部长
Shocking news, minister.
我们恐怕失去了电子监控船 圣乔治号
I'm afraid we've lost our electronic surveillance ship, the St. Georges.
昨天下午四点 我们收到例行讯息
We had a routine message at 1600 hours yesterday…
然后就音讯全无
…then nothing.
而今早我们看见漂浮的残骸
We sighted floating debris this morning.
天啊 杰克 那里的水有多深？
My God, Jack. How deep is the water there?
恐怕不够深
Not deep enough, I'm afraid.
是的 书记同志 在阿尔巴尼亚外海
Yes, Comrade Secretary. Off Albania.
是我们持续监视的 可疑英国间谍船
The suspected British spy ship which we have been monitoring.
我们能借此机会获得
It suggests that there is a chance of obtaining…
ATAC传送器
…the ATAC transmitter.
当然 同志 我们不会直接介入
Oh, of course, comrade. There will be no direct involvement…
但若流出市面 我们就不该错过
…but if it comes on the market, we should not lose…
这难能可贵的机会
…such a remarkable opportunity.
因此 我已经联络了 我们在希腊的老朋友
With that in mind, I've already contacted our usual friend in Greece.
下去吧 快点
Down you go. Go on.
下去吧
Down you go.
给我们一个吻
Give us a kiss. Give us a kiss.
我给你一颗坚果 拿去
I'll give you a nut. Here you are. Go on.
来吧
Come on.
- 你的袋子 小姐 - 谢谢
- Your packages, se?orita. - Oh, thank you.
梅丽娜
Melina!
- 谢谢 亲爱的 - 爸爸
- Thank you, darling. - Hello, Daddy.
欢迎回家 亲爱的梅丽娜
Welcome home, Melina, my darling.
- 你看起来真美 - 谢谢
- You look beautiful. - Thank you.
你从雅典打来的电话真是个惊喜
Your call from Athens was such a pleasant surprise.
能找到你们算幸运 你们突然离开克里特岛
I was lucky to find you. You left Crete so suddenly.
对 我想回来开始研究古庙
Ah, yes, I wanted to come back here and start work on the temple again.
- 你在休息吗？- 只是几天而已
- You between jobs? - Only for a few days.
- 若你有需要我可以帮忙 - 好漂亮 谢谢你
- I'll lend a hand if you want. - Darling, it's beautiful. Thank you.
这是给你的 开心果给麦斯
That's for you and pistachios for Max.
詹姆斯
James.
曼妮小姐 你真是赏心悦目
Moneypenny, a feast for my eyes.
那你身体其他部分呢？
What about the rest of you?
我正要说
Well, I was going to get around to that.
你最好进去 M在放假
You'd better go in. M's on leave…
部长和参谋总长都来了
…and the minister's arrived here with the chief of staff…
他们要立刻见你
…and wants to see you immediately.
- 我马上回来 - 我等不及了
- I'll be right back. - I can hardly wait.
你是不是忘了什么？
Oh, haven't you forgotten something?
既然M不在
Oh, well, as M's away.
你来了 007
Ah, there you are, 007.
部长 参谋总长
Minister, chief of staff.
你对ATAC系统是否了解？
Are you aware of our ATAC system, 007?
自动瞄准攻击通讯器吗？
ATAC, sir? Automatic Targeting Attack Communicator.
使用超低频符码传送器
Uses an ultra-low frequency coded transmitter…
可以下令我方潜水艇 发射弹道飞弹
…to order our submarines to launch ballistic missiles.
五天前 我方的间谍船 圣乔治号
Five days ago, our spy ship, St. Georges was sunk…
在爱奥尼亚海沉没
…in the lonian Sea.
船上装置了ATAC
She was equipped with ATAC.
若传送器落入歹人手中
If that transmitter were to fall into the wrong hands…
就会让整个北极星飞弹航队作废
…it would render our entire Polaris fleet useless.
- 所有指令都会被取消 - 更糟
- Every order could be countermanded. - Worse.
我方的潜水艇可能受命 攻击本国的城市
Our own submarines could be ordered to attack our own cities.
打捞过了吗 部长？
Have we begun a salvage operation, minister?
官方打捞行动绝不可能
An official operation was out of the question.
圣乔治号在阿尔巴尼亚外海
The St. Georges was off the Albanian coast.
我们请海洋考古学家
We asked Sir Timothy Havelock…
提摩西海夫洛 秘密搜寻船只残骸
…the marine archaeologist, to secretly locate the wreck.
在他回报结果之前 他和妻子
Before he could send in his report, he and his wife were killed…
就被古巴杀手 海克特冈泽拉刺杀身亡
…by a Cuban hit man, Hector Gonzales.
希腊警方借由两人女儿 梅丽娜的描述
The Greek police were able to identify Gonzales…
查出冈泽拉的身分背景
…from a description given to them by Melina, Sir Havelock's daughter.
这是回流行动 资料全在这里
Operation Undertow. The information's all here.
现在冈泽拉在马德里附近的别墅内
Now, Gonzales is at a villa near Madrid.
隔离他 并施与必要压力
Isolate him and apply the necessary pressure…
查出是谁雇用他
…to find out who hired him.
（最高机密）
（圣马汀）
渥尔特PPK手枪
A Walther PPk…
英国情报员的标准配备
…standard issue, British Secret Service.
可以杀人
License to kill.
或被杀
Or be killed.
把他带下去
Take him away.
无论你是谁 你已留得太久了 快走
Whoever you are, you've outstayed your welcome. Come on.
（内装防盗器）
- 希望你有开车来 - 这边走
- Well, I hope you have a car. - This way.
快点
Hurry.
- 你是谁？- 他杀了我父母
- Who are you? - He killed my parents.
海夫洛夫妇吗？我很遗憾
The Havelocks? I'm sorry.
你怎么知道冈泽拉在哪里？
How did you know where Gonzales was?
透过侦探社 你来那里做什么？
Through a detective agency. What were you doing there?
这部车的马力似乎比不上对方
I'm afraid we're being out-horsepowered.
对不起
Excuse me.
走下面那条路
Take the low road.
不用那么低
Not that low.
不介意我来开车吧？
You don't mind if I drive, do you?
先倒车 再往前 快一点
Go backwards. Forwards. Quickly.
我最爱在乡间开车 你呢？
I love a drive in the country, don't you?
抓紧
Hold tight.
对了 我们还没正式打过招呼
Oh, by the way, we haven't been properly introduced, Melina.
我是邦德 詹姆斯邦德
My name is Bond, James Bond.
奥林匹克航空十一点有班机
Olympic has a flight at 11:00.
现在去机场应该很安全
It should be safe to go to the airport now.
- 你没事吧？- 我很好 真的
- Are you all right? - I'm fine, really.
你要回父亲的船上吗？
Are you going back to your father's ship?
对 我要延续他的工作 但这件事还没了结
Yes, I'm continuing his work, but this business is still unfinished.
- 什么事？- 找出雇用冈泽拉的人
- What business? - The man who paid Gonzales.
中国人有句话说
The Chinese have a saying:
“复仇者必自绝”
"Before setting out on revenge, you first dig two graves."
我不期望你能了解
I don't expect you to understand.
你是英国人 但我是半个希腊人
You're English, but I'm half Greek.
希腊女人都像 复仇女神伊蕾克拉
And Greek women, like Electra…
永远不忘替深爱的人报仇
…always avenge their loved ones.
我该走了
I must go.
你应该去质问冈泽拉 而非让海夫洛小姐动私刑
You were meant to question Gonzales, not let Miss Havelock perforate him.
我同意 长官
I quite agree, sir.
我们必须告知首相 回流行动已经胎死腹中
We'll tell the prime minister Operation Undertow is dead in the water.
她会把我们痛骂一顿
She'll have our guts for garters.
若你再仔细看一次
If you care to look again…
报告的第二页第四段里
…at page two, paragraph four of my report, sir…
有提到我看见某人付钱给冈泽拉
…you will note that I saw someone paying off Gonzales.
假设那是刺杀海夫洛的费用
Now, assuming that that was for Havelock's murder…
那么仍有一丝希望
…then there's still a glimmer of hope.
我不了解
I don't follow.
若我们能认出那个人
If we could identify that someone…
为何不试着用辨识系统？
Why don't you try the identigraph?
- 是 长官 - 事不宜迟 007
- Yes, sir. - Get cracking, 007.
部长
Minister.
你好 Q 史密斯 手臂还好吗？
Hello, Q. Smithers, how's the arm?
复原得很好 谢谢长官关心
Coming along very nicely, thank you, sir.
真是方便
Oh, that'll come in handy.
你来这做什么 007？
What are you doing here, 007?
- 使用辨识系统 Q - 这边请
- Identigraph, Q. - This way.
- “万针嬉春”？- 不好笑 007
- Stinging in the rain? - That's not funny, 007.
你把那部莲花成功组合好了
I see you managed to get the Lotus back together again.
请不要调侃这些装备 007
I disregard these jibes about our equipment, 007.
我不认为你用它们出任务时 会觉得好笑
I don't suppose you find it funny in the field.
的确不好笑
Indeed, I don't.
这立体影像辨识系统 还在实验阶段
This 3D Visual Identigraph is still in the experimental stage.
一旦有目标的特征素描
Now, once we get a composite of the man…
就能从国际刑警 中情局
…we can find a match by patching into the photographic files…
或法国警察处的 照片资料库中找出对比
…of the Surete, Interpol, CIA, the Mossad.
还有西德警方 你已经告诉我五次了
And the West German police. You've told me so already five times.
谢谢你 007
Thank you, 007.
好
Right.
现在描述你要辨识的人
Now describe the person you wish to identify…
我就输入资讯
…and I'll program the information.
白种男性 三十多岁
Male Caucasian, late thirties.
头发柔软 淡棕色
Hair: fine, light brown.
就这样
That's it.
- 头发中分 - 等一下
- Parted in the middle. - Wait a minute.
- 好了 - 眼睛
- Right. - Eyes.
小一点
A little smaller.
蓝色 再灰一点
Blue. A little grayer.
就是这样 现在轮到鼻子
That's it. You have it. Now, nose.
- 是鼻子 不是香蕉 - 抱歉
- A nose, not a banana, Q. - I'm sorry.
停
Stop.
嘴唇再厚一点
Lips fuller.
不 嘴巴再宽一点 很好
No, no, mouth wider. Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你 莎朗
Thank you, Sharon.
- 你能走了 我来锁门 - 好
- You can go. I'll lock up. - Okay.
非常接近了 Q 现在只差眼镜
I reckon we're almost there, Q, apart from glasses.
不锈钢镜框
Steel-rimmed.
- 对 - 八角形
- Yeah. - Octagonal.
八角形
Octagonal.
就是他 他就是我们要找的人
That's him. That's our man.
好 我会找出吻合的档案
Right. I'll try and get a match.
什么事？
Yes.
我们要找的人是艾米罗克
The man we want is Emile Leopold Locque…
布鲁塞尔地下组织的推手
…an enforcer in the Brussels underworld.
他被指控数项罪名
He's been convicted of several…
都是特别残酷的谋杀案
…particularly brutal murders.
他勒死心理医生后
He escaped from Namur Prison…
从纳摩监狱脱逃
…by strangling his psychiatrist.
在马赛和香港替贩毒组织工作
He has worked for drug syndicates in Marseilles and Hong k ong.
现在据说与希腊走私贩狼疺为奸
Now reported working for Greek smugglers.
意大利情报局 认为他目前在哥迪纳
The ltalian Secret Service think that he is, at this moment, in Cortina.
我会叫驻派北义的法洛拉和你联系
I'll instruct Ferrara, our man in northern ltaly, to contact you there.
- 好 长官 - 007 不要再搞砸了
- Yes, sir. - And 007, try not to muck it up again.
我会尽力而为
I'll do my best, sir.
你锁门好了 让我出去好吗？
I'll leave you to lock up. Let me out, will you?
（托芬拿山 早上十点）
（托芬拿山）
今年在印支堡的雪比较厚
The snow this year is better at lnnsbruck.
在圣米兹的就差多了
But not at St. Moritz.
- 法拉洛 - 詹姆斯邦德
- Ferrara. - Bond. James.
路易奇
Luigi.
伦敦应该已经告知你情况
I presume London has briefed you.
若罗克在哥迪纳 我们就能找到他
If Locque's in Cortina, we'll find him.
我有个可靠的希腊联络人 他是亲英派的
I have a reliable Greek contact here, an Anglophile.
他去年协助我们破获走私集团
He helped us out last year on a smuggling operation.
- 他在哥迪纳干什么？- 他
- What's he doing in Cortina? - He…
每年在这里的小木屋度假几个月
Spends a few months a year here at his chalet.
对航运 保险 石油探勘都很熟
He's in shipping, insurance, oil exploration.
什么事都一清二楚
knows everything going on.
很可靠的人
Very reliable.
英国颁给他皇家勋章 奖励他在大战时英勇抗敌
The British gave him the king's Medal for resistance fighting during the war.
很好 我能见他吗？
Yes, but can I meet him?
我安排好了 他在奥林匹克冰宫等我们
I've set it up. He is waiting for us at the Olympic ice rink.
凯斯达图先生
Se?or kristatos.
- 凯斯达图 艾利凯斯达图 - 邦德 詹姆斯邦德
- kristatos. Ari kristatos. - Bond. James Bond.
一起坐下喝一杯好吗？
Would you care to join me in some gluhwein?
那太好了 谢谢
That's a very good idea. Thank you.
各位 有何能效劳之处？
Well, gentlemen, how can I help you?
我们需要情报
We'd like some information.
我赞助的选手
My protege. A sure winner…
下届奥运铁定得金牌
…in the next Olympics.
她非常投入在溜冰的世界
She's completely absorbed in her skating…
但对真实世界一知半解
…but innocent in the ways of the world.
她赢得金牌的那天
The day she wins the gold medal…
将会是我此生最快乐的一天
…will be the greatest in my life.
碧碧 这些是你的新仰慕者
Bibi, here are some new admirers for you.
邦德先生 法拉洛先生 这是碧碧达尔
Mr. Bond, Mr. Ferrara, Bibi Dahl…
这是教练乔可芭布林 她曾是世界级选手
…and her coach, Jacoba Brink, once a world-class skater herself.
我看过布林小姐溜冰
I've seen Miss Brink skate.
世人很快也会看见你的精采演出
I think the world will soon be seeing a great deal of your skating too.
除非她更努力一点
Only if she works harder.
- 比现在加倍努力 - 艾利叔叔
- Much harder. - Oh, Uncle Ari.
我能休息一下吗？累死了
Can I stop now? I'm pooped.
那得由布林小姐决定
That's for Miss Brink to decide.
碧碧 再练半小时
Come, Bibi, another half hour of practice.
艾利叔叔 带我去看滑雪射击好吗？
Uncle Ari, will you take me to the biathlon?
碧碧 你知道下午我得工作
Bibi, you know I have to work this afternoon.
邦德先生 碧碧想知道 你是否愿意陪她去
Bibi wants to know if you would escort her, Mr. Bond.
- 这样不太 - 若有人能陪她去
- I don't think… - I would feel better…
我就会放心很多
…if there were someone with her.
乐意之至 我住在镜子山饭店
I'd be delighted. I'm staying at the Miramonti.
太好了
Great!
我能帮两位什么忙？
Now, how can I help?
- 你认识这个人吗？- 认识 他是罗克
- Do you know this man? - Yes. Locque.
哥伦布的左右手
Columbo's right hand.
米洛哥伦布 他牵涉
Milos Columbo. His name came up in connection…
去年一项走私活动
…with a smuggling operation last year.
那是他最轻的罪状 还有毒品 贩卖人口和谋杀
That's the least of his offenses. Drugs, white slavery, contract murder.
在希腊黑道 人称他“白鸽”
In the Greek underworld, he in known as "the Dove."
真是讽刺
A very sick joke.
- 这白鸽在哪里？- 应该在希腊某处
- Where is this Dove? - Somewhere in Greece, I would guess.
我们曾经情同手足 但现在他恨我
Once we were like brothers. Now he hates me.
我们加入希腊反抗军 并肩作战
We fought together in the Greek resistance…
然后共同对抗共产党
…then against the Communists.
后来他就走上不同的路
After that, he took a different path.
感谢你拨冗 凯斯达图先生
Thank you for your time, Mr. kristatos.
我的荣幸 我很快就要去科福岛
My pleasure. I leave for Corfu soon.
有任何消息 我就会通知法拉洛先生
If I get any more information, I will call Ferrara.
路易奇 你认为怎样？这位“白鸽”哥伦布
What do you think, Luigi? Does this "Dove" Columbo…
有本事进行打捞作业吗？
…have the resources to mount a salvage operation?
当然 他在爱琴海经营 跨洋货运船队
Oh, definitely. He runs a fleet of intercoastal freighters in the Aegean.
我打个电话给米兰办公室 也许会有更多关于他的资料
I'll ring my office in Milano. They may have more on him.
- 待会见 - 好
- Luigi, I'll see you later. - Okay.
是这一支吗 小姐？
Is this the one you mean?
谢谢 我买了 替我送到克里斯塔罗饭店
Thank you. I'll take it. Deliver it to the Hotel Cristalo.
抱歉
I beg your pardon.
- 需要买什么？- 给我一打百合花
- May I help you? - Yes, give me a dozen lilies.
好吗？
Will you?
我待会再来拿
I'll pick them up later.
来 快点
Come on, quickly.
请送到他的葬礼上
Send them to the funeral, will you?
等等 你要告诉我 为何来到哥迪纳吗？
Slow down. Would you mind telling me what the devil you're doing in Cortina?
- 因为你的电报 - 什么电报？
- Your telegram. - What telegram?
上面说你找到那个人 要在今天跟我在这里碰面
It said you found the man and to meet you here today.
我没送电报
I didn't send a telegram.
上去
Now, get in.
请到车站
The station, please.
- 我们要走了吗？- 不是“我们” 是你要离开
- Are we leaving? - Not "we." You. And now.
你别想命令我
You don't tell me what to do.
你找到雇用冈泽拉的人了吗？
Did you find the man who hired Gonzales?
我正在努力
I'm working on it.
他在这里 对不对？
He's here, isn't he?
这就是你来的原因 司机 马上回头
That's why you're here. Driver, stop! Go back!
- 我要留下 - 以便亲手宰了他？
- I'm staying. - So you can put an arrow in his back?
如果你这样做 就休想找到幕后主使
Do that and we'll never find out who or what is behind all this.
死的是我父母 不是你的 让我下车 停车
It was my parents they killed, not yours. Let me out. Driver, stop!
梅丽娜 看着我
Melina, look at me.
上次算你运气好 但他们已经盯上你
You were lucky once, but they are onto you now.
电报和刚才那些摩托车 都能证明
The telegram, the motorcycles back there. They prove it.
- 让我处理 - 你？为何牵扯到你？
- Let me handle this. - You? How are you involved?
我只能说此事严重关系到 你我两国的利益
All I can tell you is it's something of vital interest to both our countries.
比我父母的死更重要？
More important than my parents?
你父亲也有参与
Your father was part of it.
他认为此事 值得让他付出生命
He thought it important enough to risk his life.
梅丽娜 请相信我
Now, Melina, please trust me.
回翠亚娜号上等我
Go back to the Triaina and wait.
我会尽力调查 然后就直接回到科福岛
Let me find out what I can here, then I'll come straight to Corfu.
- 我保证 - 好
- I promise you. - Okay.
我会回去等 但别让我等太久
I'll go back and wait, but not for long.
不会的 我保证
It won't be, I swear.
在冰宫没有淋浴设备吗？
Don't they have showers at the ice rink?
你怎么进来的？
How did you get in here?
有一个门房是我的粉丝
One of the porters is a fan.
他愿意为我做任何事 我也愿意为你做任何事
He'll do anything for me, and I'll do anything for you.
我受宠若惊 碧碧
Well, I'm exceedingly flattered, Bibi…
但你正在受训
…but you're in training.
真好笑 大家都知道嘿咻 可以增强肌肉性能
That's a laugh. Everybody knows it builds up muscle tone.
那借由穿衣服
How about building up a little more muscle tone…
来增强如何？
…by putting on your clothes?
你不喜欢我？
Don't you like me?
你是个很棒的女孩 碧碧
I think you're wonderful, Bibi…
但你的艾利叔叔 应该不会赞成
…but I don't think your Uncle Ari would approve.
他？他以为我还是处女
Him? He thinks I'm still a virgin.
你快把衣服穿上 我去买冰淇淋给你吃
Yes, well, you get your clothes on, and I'll buy you an ice cream.
走吧
Shall we?
你从来不用换气吗？
Don't you ever come up for air?
这就是我会得到金牌的原因 我很会控制呼吸
That's why I'll get the gold medal: breath control.
是啊 你输不了
Yes, well, you can't lose.
现在上场的是艾瑞克格
And now, Erich Kriegler…
去年东欧滑雪射击冠军
…last year's East European champion.
那就是艾瑞克格
There's Erich kriegler.
东欧冠军？
The East German champion?
他很帅对不对？
Isn't he beautiful?
碧碧 你知道吗？你真是善变
You know something, Bibi? You're fickle.
艾瑞
Hey, Erich!
来吧 我们去看他射击
Come on, let's go watch him shoot.
我们可以在终点喝一杯
We'll have a drink at the finish.
碧碧 我得先行离开了
Well, Bibi, I'm afraid I have to leave you.
- 不 留下来陪我 - 我和人有约
- No, James, stay with me. - I have an appointment.
你等一下会去练习场 和我道别吗？
Will you come and say goodbye to me at the practice rink later?
拜托 詹姆斯 我们很快就要回希腊了
Please, James, we're going back to Greece soon.
好吧 但若我来不及
All right, but if I can't make it…
我只能说 别再长大了
…all I can say is don't grow up any more.
你会让异性受不了
The opposite sex won't survive it.
我不会去太久
Won't take long.
- 别乱按那些按钮 - 好
- Don't play with any of the switches. - Right.
詹姆斯
James.
你怎么这么久才来？
James, what took you so long?
我走风景比较美的路
I took the scenic route.
谈谈你的男朋友艾瑞克格
Tell me more about your boyfriend, Erich kriegler.
他不抽烟 只吃健康食品 甚至不和女生讲话
He doesn't smoke, he only eats health foods and he won't even talk to girls.
詹姆斯 你在忌妒
James, you're jealous.
当然 你还能多谈谈 我这位情敌吗？
Of course. What else can you tell me about my rival for your affections?
听说他叛逃东德
They say he's a defector from East Germany.
碧碧 该去按摩了
Bibi, it is time for your rubdown.
真想把你生吞活剥
I could eat you up alive.
保重 邦德 我们还会再见面
Farewell, Mr. Bond, but not goodbye.
我六点就会办完事 在这里等我
I'll be finished around 6:00. Meet me here.
你怎么知道我在这里？
How did you know I was here?
我打电话到翠亚娜号 他们说你到岸上了
I radio telephoned the Triaina, and they told me you were coming ashore.
我得替船员采购用品 一起来吧 顺便聊聊
I have to go shopping for the crew. Come with me, we can talk.
有何不可？
Why not?
谢谢
Thank you.
你可能用得着
I think you may need that.
我父亲生前最爱在这看风景
My father loved the view from here.
- 我想像得到 - 我们常来
- I can see why. - We came here often.
- 科福岛是你家吗？- 不是
- Is Corfu your home? - No.
我真正的家是翠亚娜号 希腊诸岛
My real home's always been the Triaina, the Greek islands…
土耳其 北非 随着父亲的工作浪迹天涯
…Turkey, North Africa, wherever my father's work took us.
他有留下任何资料吗？也许对我们有帮助
Did he leave any notes? They could help us.
应该没有
No, I don't think so.
老实说
To tell the truth…
他死后我一直没勇气 进入他的书房
…I haven't had the courage to go into his study since.
尽量别去想这件事了
Try not to think about it now.
今晚我要去赌场见个人 他也许能提供线索
I'm meeting a man tonight at the casino who may give us a lead.
你在流汗 邦奇
You're perspiring, Bunky.
女伯爵
Good evening, contessa.
五十万
500, 000.
才一半？你的勇气上哪去了 邦奇？
Only half? Where's your courage, Bunky?
勇气敌不过很背的手气 女伯爵
Courage is no match for an unfriendly shoe, countess.
这才对 邦奇
Bravo, Bunky.
你今晚运气很好
Lucky night.
维持现状赢面较大
The odds favor standing pat.
照机率而言是如此
If you play the odds.
帮我换成现金好吗？
Would you cash these in for me, please?
谢谢 失陪了
Thank you. Excuse me.
要餐前酒吗？
Aperitif, please?
我要一杯乌索
Ouzo for me, please.
和一杯威士忌
And a whiskey.
要吃点什么？
And to eat?
虾球 沙拉和法式牛肉
I'll have the prawns, salad and Bourdetto.
很好的选择 我也一样
An excellent choice. I'll have the same.
我推荐家乡的白酒 让你品尝好吗？
May I suggest a white wine from my home place?
抱歉 白酒味道太浓了
If you'll forgive me, that's a little too scented for my palate.
我比较喜欢菲泰基
I prefer the Theotaki Aspro.
上次会面后 我一直问我自己
After our last meeting, I am asking myself…
你为何要知道 哥伦布左右手罗克的事
…why you want to know about Locque, Columbo's man.
我知道哥伦布将海洛因在此加工
I know Columbo runs heroin to be refined here…
然后再走私到英国
…before it's sent to England.
我想我知道原因了
So I think I see the answer.
你是英国缉毒单位派来的
You're from the British Narcotics Board.
我说得对吗？
Am I right?
继续说
Go on.
祝你好运 我的朋友
I wish you luck, my friend.
但我得警告你 要阻止哥伦布并下容易
But I must warn you, stopping Columbo will be difficult.
他后台很硬 没办法说逮捕就逮捕
He has important connections. You cannot just arrest him.
你得想别的办法
You must find a different way.
也许得杀了他
You may have to kill him.
你气馁了吗？
Does this discourage you?
- 告诉我他的下落 - 就在那里
- Just tell me where he is. - Over there.
和穿蓝衣的女士在一起
With the woman in blue.
我俩形同陌路 但我要你见见他
We ignore each other, but I wanted you to see him.
他是这座赌场的秘密合伙人 但我们非常安全
He is a secret partner in this casino. But we are perfectly safe.
他在自己的地盘不会轻举妄动
He will do nothing in his own place.
那位女伯爵呢？
And the countess?
她是丽索 奥地利人
Lisl, an Austrian.
昂贵的情妇 有时为赌场作诱饵
Expensive mistress. She sometimes shills for the house.
如果那是别人的钱的话
If she bets it's with other people's money.
但我得警告你 要阻止哥伦布并下容易
But I must warn you, stopping Columbo will be difficult.
他后台很硬 没办法说逮捕就逮捕
He has important connections. You cannot just arrest him.
你得想别的办法
You must find a different way.
也许得杀了他
You may have to kill him.
你气馁了吗？
Does this discourage you?
告诉我他的下落
Just tell me where he is.
你真是恶心 竟敢这样和我说话？
You are a disgusting man. How dare you talk to me like that?
我想怎么说都行 给我坐下
I will speak to you any way I please. Sit down.
不要出洋相
You're making a spectacle of yourself.
出去
Get out!
我求之不得
Nothing would please me more.
- 这也许是好机会 - 也许是个陷阱
- This may be an opportunity. - This may be a trap.
照机率而言是如此
If you play the odds.
好 用我的车吧 我去玩几局
As you wish. Take my car. I'll play a little chemin.
叫司机回来接我
Ask the chauffeur to come back for me.
让我来
Allow me.
有荣幸送你回家吗？
May I drive you home?
不用了 谢谢 我坐计程车就行
No, thank you. I'll take a taxi.
你害怕吗？
No courage?
老实说 这可是千载难逢的机会
Seriously, you may have a job finding one at this time.
你看起来像个绅士
Well, you look like a gentleman.
有何不可？
Why not?
我是女伯爵丽索冯斯拉
I am the Countess Lisl Von Schlaf.
我叫邦德
My name is Bond.
我在写关于希腊毒贩的小说 你认识一些吗？
I'm writing a novel about Greek smugglers. know any?
毒贩？我怎么可能认识
Smugglers? How would I know any smugglers?
我认为你这种身分地位的女士
I would think that a lady in your position…
应该人脉相当广
…would get to know many things.
我会相当感激
I'd be most grateful.
有多感激？
How grateful?
非常感激
Very.
我欣赏知恩图报的男人
I adore grateful men.
明天打给你好吗 女伯爵？
May I call you tomorrow, countess?
我是夜猫子 冰箱里有香槟和生蚝
I'm a night person. I have champagne and oysters in the fridge.
要进来吃点宵夜吗？
Why not come in for a bite?
今晚你的服务到此为止
I won't need you anymore tonight.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Bottoms up.
糟糕
Whoops!
我的睡衣好滑
Me nightie's slipping.
你的口音也是 女伯爵
So is your accent, countess.
- 曼彻斯特？- 很接近
- Manchester? - Close.
利物浦
Liverpool.
你和这件衣服的主人的
It was an amusing performance…
互动很有趣
…between you and the owner of this.
哥伦布到底对你说了什么？
What exactly did Columbo whisper to you?
他说你是间谍 要我去打探你的底细
That you're a spy. To find out more about you.
你探到了吗？
And have you?
你说呢
Have I ever.
你离开时可以开我的车
When you're ready to leave, you can take my car.
你好像在下逐客令
That sounds like a dismissal.
我希望能和你共享早餐
I was looking forward to breakfast.
丽索 回来
Lisl! Lisl, come back!
上车
Get in!
再见了 女伯爵
Goodbye, countess.
什么
What?
- 我该怎么处置你？- 没办法说逮捕就逮捕
- What should I do with you? - You cannot just arrest him.
你得想别的办法
You must find a different way.
也许得杀了他
You may have to kill him.
你气馁了吗？
Does this discourage you?
告诉我他的下落
Just tell me where he is.
我就在这里 英国情报员邦德先生
I'm here, Mr. Bond of the British Secret Service.
但我告诉你
But I'll tell you…
你要找的人是凯斯达图 不是我
…it is kristatos you want, not me.
他讲的是他自己
He told you about himself.
后台硬的人其实是他
He's the one with the powerful connections.
罗克替他工作 不是我
Locque works for him, not for me.
我是走私没错 我走私黄金 钻石
I smuggle, yes. I smuggle gold, diamonds…
香烟 开心果
…cigarettes, pistachio nuts…
但绝对没有海洛因
…but no heroin.
坐下 贩毒的事我留给他去做
Sit down. That I leave to him…
当他没有忙着替苏联
…when he is not too busy working for Russia…
对抗你或我国家的时候
…against my country and yours.
我的国家颁给他皇家勋章
My country awarded him the king's Medal.
我知道 但其他人为这勋章送命
Yes, I know. But other people died for it.
在希腊战争中 他是个双面谍
During the fighting in Crete, he was a double agent.
皇家勋章
king's Medal.
若不是替可怜的丽索难过
I would laugh if my heart was not so heavy…
我一定会笑出来
…about my poor Lisl.
凯斯图达设计你 有什么好处？
What does kristatos gain by setting you up?
我知道太多他的事
Well, I know too much about him.
他不希望我成为绊脚石
He wants me out of the way.
利用英国情报员借刀杀人
By using a British agent to do his dirty work for him…
你的政府搞不好还会 再给他一个勋章
…your government might give him another medal.
- 我为何该相信你？- 今晚我就能证明
- Why should I believe you? - I'll prove it to you tonight.
我们一起去
We'll go together to his warehouse…
他在阿尔巴尼亚的仓库如何？
…in Albania, okay?
若我明早前不回报
If I don't report in by morning…
英国和全希腊警察
…not only my people, but the entire Greek police will be down on you…
都会对你穷追猛打
…like a load of bricks.
别担心
Don't worry.
到了明天 我们就会变成好朋友
By tomorrow, we'll be good friends.
为友谊喝一杯吧
Let us drink to that.
我明天再喝好了
I'll wait till tomorrow.
你或许需要这个
You may need this.
我看人很准
I'm a good judge of men.
邦德先生 你有希腊人所说的
Mr. Bond, you have what the Greeks call tha'ros.
胆量
Guts.
你也是 哥伦布先生
So have you, Mr. Columbo.
干杯
Cheers.
山多斯的药局
Santos' drug store.
小心
Watch it.
吉姆潜水装备
J.I.M. diving equipment…
用于超过海深三百尺的 打捞工作
…for salvage work at depths of over 300 feet.
生鸦片
Raw opium.
老毒贩的把戏 凯斯达图全都很在行
An old smuggler's trick. kristatos knows them all.
带你的手下离开这里
Get your men out of here.
马上
Now.
我相信这是你留给法洛拉的
You left this with Ferrara, I believe.
他对高度没有概念
Had no head for heights.
圣乔治号在哪里沉没的？
Where did the St. Georges sink?
我们不确定 只知道在这附近
We can't be sure for certain. We know it was in this vicinity.
你父亲利用古庙当作掩护
Your father was using the temple as a front.
凯斯达图将你父亲灭口
kristatos killed your father…
他就无法抢先一步找到圣乔治号
…so he wouldn't find the St. Georges before he did.
凯斯达图 我能帮上什么忙？
kristatos. How can I help?
你父亲把航海日志放在哪里？
Where does your father keep his daily log?
日志
Daily log.
我父亲和他是三十年的老朋友 他每句话都会重覆
Father and he were pals for 30 years. He repeats everything.
- 给我们一个吻 - 他叫什么名字？
- Give us a kiss. - What's his name?
麦斯
Max.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Hello.
全都是速记
It's all shorthand.
他用独特速记法 只有我会解读
He used a special kind. Only I could decipher it.
他乘坐海王星号数度去勘查
He made several surveys in Neptune.
- 什么海王星？- 一艘双人潜艇
- What's Neptune? - Our two-man submarine.
他写说看见了潜水钟
He saw a diving bell here.
潜水钟？
Diving bell?
勘采石油用的 是凯斯达图
Oil exploration. kristatos.
三天后 他在同样地方看到残骸
Three days later, he sighted a wreck in the same area.
然后呢？
And?
这是他最后一笔速记
That was his last entry.
当天他就遭杀害
The day he was killed.
在那种深度空气没用 我们需要氧氦混合气
Air would be useless at this depth. We need a mixture of oxygen and helium.
我有所有必需的装置
I have the necessary equipment.
这件事越少人知道越好
The less people that know, the better.
我会叫船员休假去 除了大副和两名员工以外
I'll give the crew shore leave except for the mate and two others.
我们着手吧
Let's go.
（圣乔治号 法勒他）
584尺
584 feet.
氧氦混合气能撑八分钟 我们动作要快
An oxygen-helium mix will give us eight minutes. We'll have to work fast.
船员不会把传送器毁了吗？
Wouldn't the crew have destroyed the transmitter?
除非他们有机会设定引爆器
Only if they'd had the chance to set the explosive timer.
下面有访客
We have a visitor below.
节省气体 必要时才说话
Conserve your gas supply. Speak only when necessary.
希望他是独自觅食
I hope he was dining alone.
你最好回到潜水艇
Go back to the sub.
不 我要留下
No, no. I'm staying.
那应该是控制舱
That should be the command cabin.
找到了
Eureka!
主要自动摧毁装置
"Main destruct timer…
在ATAC杠杆右边 双重装置
…under lever right of ATAC housing, dualled…
透过反操纵充电器 使主电路失效
…by ring main circuit through anti-handling charger."
自动摧毁装置设定在一分钟
The destruct timer's set at one minute.
不知为何杠杆没有拉下
For some reason, the lever wasn't pulled.
热力充电的传送器
The transmitter with a thermite charge.
拿着
Hold these.
要绕过电震板
"To bypass trembler switch…
按下列次序剪电线
…cut wires in following procedure."
剪刀
Cutters.
螺丝起子
Screwdriver.
好了 我们离开这里
That's it. Let's get out of here.
詹姆斯 救命
James, help!
- 詹姆斯 我撑不下去 - 我们都能撑过去
- James, I won't make it. - We both will.
快回潜水艇 我来拖延他
Get to the sub. I'll stall him.
詹姆斯！
James!
尝试关掉二氧化碳
Try and close the CO2.
我正在努力
I'm trying.
小心点 詹姆斯 它可有五千年历史
Careful, James. It's 5000 years old.
谢谢你 邦德先生
Thank you, Mr. Bond.
你替我们省了拆除的麻烦
You have saved us the trouble of disarming it.
阿帕 拿过来
Apostis, take that.
我船上的船员呢？
Where are my men?
你很快就会去见他们
You will be joining them.
让她走
Let the girl go.
我们会付你双倍酬劳
We'll double whatever you're getting.
我从来不毁约
I never go back on a deal.
以免声誉受损
It would be bad for my reputation.
我会负责送达 并把钱带回来
I will deliver it and return with the money.
真像苏联国安局情报员的风格 依照协议 地点由我决定
The voice of the k GB. Our agreement was that I designate the meeting place.
他们付钱后 我就交出传送器
After they pay, I will give them the transmitter.
绝不能让它离开你的视线
It must not be let out of your sight.
或是我的视线 我们要去哪里？
Nor mine. Where are we going?
我们要把ATAC带到圣西洛
We will take the ATAC to St. CyriI's.
圣西洛？我来安排收货事宜
St. CyriI's. I'll arrange the pickup.
伤口绑紧一点
Bind that wound.
我们还不想让血流到水里
We don't want blood in the water. Not yet.
凶手
Murderer.
你已经技穷了 海夫洛小姐
You have shot your last bolt, Miss Havelock.
脚不用绑了
Leave their legs free.
双腿是美味的诱饵
They'll make appetizing bait.
没想到会是这种结局
I didn't think it would end like this.
我们还没死
We're not dead yet.
抓紧
Hold tight.
回头 再来一次
Turn around. We go again.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
再一次 快点
Once again. Hurry.
救命
Help!
别管他了
Ah, leave him.
回头 压过去
Turn. Run them down.
跟我来
Follow me.
鲨鱼把他们吃了 回码头去吧
The sharks have them. Make port.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Hello.
- 给我一个吻 - 麦斯 现在别闹
- Give us a kiss. - Max, not now.
凯斯达图还没死
kristatos is still alive.
也许正在去莫斯科 或哈瓦纳的途中
And probably headed to Moscow or Havana by now.
我们永远逮不到他了
We'll never get him.
或是ATAC
Or the ATAC.
ATAC到圣西洛
ATAC to St. CyriI's. ATAC to St. CyriI's.
（圣西洛）
原谅我犯的罪 神父
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
你太轻描淡写了 007
That's putting it mildly, 007.
你的消息令人吃惊
Your signal sent Whitehall into shock.
目前我们在希腊 已经找到
So far we have managed to locate…
439个圣西洛
…439 St. CyriI's in Greece.
谁知道凯斯达图把ATAC 藏在哪一个
Heaven only knows to which one kristatos took the ATAC.
我知道一个消息灵通的人 能提供线索 Q
I know a well-informed person to contact about that, Q.
圣西洛 我们以前都在那躲避德军
St. CyriI's, where we used to hide from the Germans.
只有凯斯达图会把废弃修道院
Only kristatos would make an abandoned monastery…
当成避难所
…his personal retreat.
我的朋友 为了这特别的场合
My friend, I've been studying this place for years…
我已经研究这里好久了
…for just such an occasion.
我们在这里分开 好吗？
We'll split here, huh?
你们最好从右翼接近 距离建筑比较远
Your best approach is on the right face, away from the building.
然后必须设法到左边的
Then make towards the shed on the left…
小屋 那里有电线和电苐
…which houses the basket and the electronic winch.
只能从小屋里操作
It can be operated only from the shed.
祝你好运
Good luck.
应该多带点人手来
Should have brought more people.
- 詹姆斯希望有奇迹发生 - 我们只有五个人
- James is counting on surprise. - But we are only five men.
还有一个女人
And one woman.
十八
Eighteen…
十九
…nineteen…
二十
…twenty.
- 再做50下 - 真讨厌
- Fifty more. - That's the pits!
我本该在奥斯陆的 因斯布鲁克溜冰
I'm supposed to be skating in Oslo, in lnnsbruck.
我们在这阴森的地方干嘛？
Why are we in this creepy place?
计划改变 我们要去古巴住几个月
Our plans are changed. We are going to live in Cuba for a few months.
- 古巴？- 你就能专心溜冰
- Cuba! - You can skate without distractions.
我会当观众
I'll be your audience.
真是碍事 我要赢金牌
What a drag. I want to win the gold medal.
我们都希望你得金牌
We all want that.
我知道你要什么
I know what you want.
但你对我而言太老了 我要离开
But you're too old for me. I'm splitting.
你怂恿她和我作对
You have done this. Poisoned her against me!
别恼羞成怒 艾利叔叔
Don't blow your top, Ari.
- 少烦她 - 我会和你算帐
- Leave her alone. - I will deal with you, Jacoba Brink…
就像对付那些背叛我的人一样
…as I deal with everyone who betrays me.
碧碧
Bibi…
你好年轻
…you're so young.
一定得有赞助人
You must have a sponsor.
我会另外再找一个
I'll find another one.
出去查看一下
Go outside and check the guards.
直升机到了马上通知我
Let me know as soon as the helicopter arrives.
凯斯达图手下的杀手之一
One of kristatos' killers.
让他闭嘴
Shut him up.
把门关上
Get the door.
走吧 乔治 走吧
Come on, George. Let's go.
快点 除非你要我把你丢下
Hurry, unless you want me to go without you.
你很清楚我绝不会离开你
You know, I will never leave you.
你的将军迟到了
Your general is late.
只有恶劣天候才会耽误他
Only bad weather would delay him.
看好窗户
Cover the windows.
我们动手吧
Let's go.
他没事的 不用管他
He's all right. Leave him.
他没事
He's all right.
退后
Back!
好 走吧
Okay. Let's go.
我就跟在后面
I'll be with you.
抱歉
Sorry.
关上门
Cover the door!
凯斯达图呢？回答小声一点
Where's kristatos? And keep your voice down.
我们要离开他 走之前绝不能让他知道
We are leaving him. He mustn't know until we are gone.
若你帮我们 我们就协助你
We'll help you if you help us.
来
Come.
守卫在哪里？
Where are the guards?
那边
That way.
在这里等
Wait here.
快走
Move!
- 凯斯达图在哪里？- 广场的另一边
- Where's kristatos? - The other side of the courtyard.
你最好留在这
You better stay here.
布林小姐呢？你把她怎么了？
Where's Brink? What have you done to her?
- 回房去 - 你下地狱去吧
- Go back to your room! - You can go to hell!
放下武器
Drop it.
- 凯斯达图在哪里？- 带着ATAC走了
- Where's kristatos? - He's left with the ATAC.
你得付出代价
You're going to pay for it.
你不像以前一样灵活了
You're not as fast as you used to be.
不 梅丽娜 这不是解决办法
No, Melina, that's not the answer.
我们要把他交给希腊警方
We'll turn him over to the Greek police.
少挡路 詹姆斯
Out of my way, James.
好吧
All right…
但你得准备好挖两座坟
…but be prepared to dig those two graves.
别激动 同志
That's detente, comrade.
你得不到 我也得不到
You don't have it. I don't have it.
碧碧似乎找到新赞助人了
It seems as though Bibi has a new sponsor.
- 进展如何？- 我已经布好了一条
- How's it going? - I've patched through…
机密的卫星线
…a high security line to the satellite.
可以尝试联络邦德
We can try Bond now.
好 接通十号了吗？
Good. Are you through to Number 10?
在待命 长官
Standing by, sir.
你知道我想做什么吗？
You know what I'd like?
我无法想像
I can't imagine.
在月光下游泳
A moonlight swim.
007 你在吗？
007, are you there?
邦德 听到了吗？
Bond, are you there?
全为了你 亲爱的
For your eyes only, darling.
- 他在 - 接首相
- He's there. - Patch in the prime minister.
我来接 丹尼斯
I'll get it, Denis.
你好
Hello.
邦德先生在线上 首相
Mr. Bond on the line, prime minister.
邦德先生
Ah, Mr. Bond…
我想亲自致电给你
…I wanted to call you personally and to say how pleased…
很高兴这次任务圆满成功 谢谢你
…we all are that your mission was a success, thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you, thank you.
别谢我 邦德先生 你的勇气和机智
Don't thank me, Mr. Bond. Your courage and resourcefulness…
是国家的光荣
…are a credit to the nation.
丹尼斯和我都很期待与你会面
Denis and I look forward to meeting you.
同时 若有我能效劳之处
Meanwhile, if there is anything I can do for you…
给我们一个吻
Give us a kiss, give us a kiss.
你真是的 邦德先生
Well, really, Mr. Bond.
我想线路有点问题 首相
I think we're having a little trouble with the line, madam.
白痴 再呼叫一次
You idiot. Get on to him.
007. 007.
邦德？！你疯了吗？什么事情？
Bond?! Have you gone mad? What's going on?
邦德…
Bond?! Bond?! Bond?!